<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>People on Sebastian Cavada</title><link>https://sebo-the-tramp.github.io/categories/people/</link><description>Recent content in People on Sebastian Cavada</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 10:21:13 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sebo-the-tramp.github.io/categories/people/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My first hackathon in the UAE - Pioneers 4.0 - (🏆 WINNER)</title><link>https://sebo-the-tramp.github.io/03_projects/edge-hackathon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 10:21:13 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://sebo-the-tramp.github.io/03_projects/edge-hackathon/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://sebo-the-tramp.github.io/03_projects/edge-hackathon/image.png" alt="Featured image of post My first hackathon in the UAE - Pioneers 4.0 - (🏆 WINNER)" />&lt;h1 id="my-first-hackathon-in-the-uae">My first Hackathon in the UAE
&lt;/h1>&lt;p>I had the opportunity to participate in the Pioneers4.0 Hackathon, organized by the Edge together with MoAT and partner LIPTON tea. It was a 72-hour event, where we had to develop an optimization solution to optimize the production and blending of tea.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was part of a team of 5 people, and we were able to develop a solution that was able to optimize the production of tea, considering the different types of tea and the different blends that could be made. We used a simple rule-based algorithm to optimize the production and blending of tea, and we were able to present a working prototype at the end of the event.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was a great experience, and I was able to learn a lot about the tea industry and the challenges that the industry faces. I also learned a lot about the different types of tea and the different blends that can be made. It was a great opportunity to work with a team of people from different backgrounds and to learn from each other.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We also managed to win the competition with a mix of team-work, creativity as well as technical skills. It was a great experience and I am looking forward to participating in more hackathons in the future.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks to the Edge and MoAT for organizing the event, and to LIPTON tea as well. I am looking forward to be part of the LIPTON team in the future, with the internship that I was awarded at the end of the event.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Following some pictures of the event:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://sebo-the-tramp.github.io/03_projects/edge-hackathon/image.png"
width="2996"
height="1096"
srcset="https://sebo-the-tramp.github.io/03_projects/edge-hackathon/image_hu3037950491188731137.png 480w, https://sebo-the-tramp.github.io/03_projects/edge-hackathon/image_hu12029488097392795760.png 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="All the participants together on the stage"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="273"
data-flex-basis="656px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://sebo-the-tramp.github.io/03_projects/edge-hackathon/4358450C-DA13-475C-9BA4-BC8770002C19.JPG"
width="3840"
height="2160"
srcset="https://sebo-the-tramp.github.io/03_projects/edge-hackathon/4358450C-DA13-475C-9BA4-BC8770002C19_hu7768972869191826713.JPG 480w, https://sebo-the-tramp.github.io/03_projects/edge-hackathon/4358450C-DA13-475C-9BA4-BC8770002C19_hu5647556701346842885.JPG 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Our winning proof"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="177"
data-flex-basis="426px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://sebo-the-tramp.github.io/03_projects/edge-hackathon/089cbd28-e8b9-49dd-aff7-73d60c499fd1.JPG"
width="4032"
height="2268"
srcset="https://sebo-the-tramp.github.io/03_projects/edge-hackathon/089cbd28-e8b9-49dd-aff7-73d60c499fd1_hu13038122089877568271.JPG 480w, https://sebo-the-tramp.github.io/03_projects/edge-hackathon/089cbd28-e8b9-49dd-aff7-73d60c499fd1_hu17815644352049799312.JPG 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Our amazing team, from left to right (people holding the cerificate): Luthfi Shahab, me, Segni Desalegn, Sara Abdulbasit, Mariam Alzaabi and Siti Maghfirotul Ulyah"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="177"
data-flex-basis="426px"
>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MBZUAI entrepreneurship school</title><link>https://sebo-the-tramp.github.io/03_projects/mbzuai-entrepreneurship/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 10:21:13 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://sebo-the-tramp.github.io/03_projects/mbzuai-entrepreneurship/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://sebo-the-tramp.github.io/03_projects/mbzuai-entrepreneurship/1706553055846.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post MBZUAI entrepreneurship school" />&lt;p>🚀 A Milestone at the Entrepreneurship Pitch Day 🌟&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What an enriching experience for WellRound during last week&amp;rsquo;s Pitch Day organized by MBZUAI (Mohamed bin Zayed University of Artificial Intelligence) and startAD as the conclusion of the MBZUAI Entrepreneurship Course. Our journey was packed with learning and invaluable insights!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The chance to present our AI-driven idea to the esteemed jury members Jean-Luc Scherer, Sultan Al Hajji, Selim Tira, Dr Ramzi BEN OUAGHREM and Michael Huang was both challenging and rewarding. Their feedback is a treasure trove, guiding our next steps.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kudos to everyone at StartAD for the great opportunity, in particular, a huge thanks to Flo Akinbiyi, Adnan Dekedek, and Jenny Li for their enthusiasm and expert guidance!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A big shoutout to the winners for their amazing pitches and ideas, and to everyone that participated!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My colleagues Akbobek Abilkaiyrkyzy, Sathya R, and I are already gearing up for our Wellround&amp;rsquo;s next iteration, inspired and more focused than ever.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>🔑 Key Takeaways:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Embrace every piece of feedback for growth.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Each pitch sharpens our vision and storytelling.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Collaboration fuels innovation.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://sebo-the-tramp.github.io/03_projects/mbzuai-entrepreneurship/1706553055846.jpeg"
width="2048"
height="1152"
srcset="https://sebo-the-tramp.github.io/03_projects/mbzuai-entrepreneurship/1706553055846_hu6257078364664368816.jpeg 480w, https://sebo-the-tramp.github.io/03_projects/mbzuai-entrepreneurship/1706553055846_hu976951420474417839.jpeg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="All the 2023 fall class of the MBZUAI Entrepreneurship school"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="177"
data-flex-basis="426px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://sebo-the-tramp.github.io/03_projects/mbzuai-entrepreneurship/1706553050531.jpeg"
width="2048"
height="1365"
srcset="https://sebo-the-tramp.github.io/03_projects/mbzuai-entrepreneurship/1706553050531_hu7245333940414877949.jpeg 480w, https://sebo-the-tramp.github.io/03_projects/mbzuai-entrepreneurship/1706553050531_hu4621521240127584442.jpeg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Receiving the certificate"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="150"
data-flex-basis="360px"
>
&lt;img src="https://sebo-the-tramp.github.io/03_projects/mbzuai-entrepreneurship/1706553058940.jpeg"
width="2048"
height="1365"
srcset="https://sebo-the-tramp.github.io/03_projects/mbzuai-entrepreneurship/1706553058940_hu16103162977852578918.jpeg 480w, https://sebo-the-tramp.github.io/03_projects/mbzuai-entrepreneurship/1706553058940_hu872847728078529929.jpeg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="A cool photo! In reality I was really trembling"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="150"
data-flex-basis="360px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://sebo-the-tramp.github.io/03_projects/mbzuai-entrepreneurship/1706553057219.jpeg"
width="2048"
height="1365"
srcset="https://sebo-the-tramp.github.io/03_projects/mbzuai-entrepreneurship/1706553057219_hu162178263792267735.jpeg 480w, https://sebo-the-tramp.github.io/03_projects/mbzuai-entrepreneurship/1706553057219_hu6058965238694885698.jpeg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Our amazing team, from left to right: me, Akbobek Abilkaiyrkyzy and Sathyamoorthy Rajendran"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="150"
data-flex-basis="360px"
>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Euregio Brussels school</title><link>https://sebo-the-tramp.github.io/03_projects/contexts/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2023 10:21:13 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://sebo-the-tramp.github.io/03_projects/contexts/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://sebo-the-tramp.github.io/03_projects/contexts/cover.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post Euregio Brussels school" />&lt;h1 id="part-1---the-plane">Part 1 - the plane
&lt;/h1>&lt;p>I am writing from the plane. I am in the first row in the middle. I feel I am very lucky. My week of lectures has ended this morning with a discussion on the migration problem in the EU. It was something I have never experienced because we had to take the side of the politicians that don’t accept or better want to protect the EU from immigration. Usually this is the opposite to what I think and it was good for me to push myself out of the bubble and try to see everything from a new prospective. I can’t lie that it was difficult to be in the shoes of people that uses hate and aversion towards the different and the unknown to get votes and get things done, because this is what it does boil down to.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During this experience I really felt what it is to be on the other side and even more I realize how much I tend to be a “super-part” everyday life. Here is where the inception happens. Through meditation I learned to be equanimous and be balanced on most topics. Then reading the book “reality transurfing” in the past weeks I learned how wise and useful it is not to take any side in discussion or idealisms. And in the end this week I experienced the importance of taking a side and trying to be on the side of the right. And here I also see both the arguments to take a position and not to take a position. I am equanimous. According to the meditation we should always have in mind to reduce suffering and that’s what I have in mind for the future and I would always like to deploy all my resources towards this goal.
As a concluding anecdote, I wanted to share my experience with homeless people I met in Bruxelles, because yes where the most money are the most poverty is as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This homeless people where there on the streets and I wanted to do anything to help. Probably I didn’t. I could have shared a loaf of bread that in the end I had to throw away. I could have brought them some items I have bought from too good to go, but I felt it was wrong and I felt embarrassed, but most of all I didn’t know if that was the right way to act. In this regard I think there is no, or very little, actions that can be done at that very moment to solve something, but I am a big fun of compounded interest and doing small, or big, things over a long period of time in order to really solve a problem.
This proved to be successful different times. Especially I realized this with my education: there was no single thing that I could have done different, because in the end they brought me at this point. Now I really want to focus only on a handful things, do them at a very high level and be able then to give value to many through my work and time. With this I want to say that we are in this together, we are all excellent at speaking or writing, but will we have the courage to act and really put our words into actions?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I hope so and I will bring this experience with me and use it as a tool for my next decisions to be aligned with the goal of giving the most and making this place a little better because of my presence. If I could help a single person than my goal will be fulfilled.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are in a cloud now, there is some turbulence and I will have to close now.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="part-2---the-train">Part 2 - the train
&lt;/h1>&lt;p>I start to write the second and conclusive part here in the train. I was able to get a good train going to Pandora and I am still active and I feel I would like to write or relax.
I still don’t believe what happened on the plane. It is so strange, yet so beautiful. Some times I think is karma other I just understand that it is only a coincidence. Maybe it was just how the algorithms of Ryanair works in assigning random places. Actually it probably don’t assign random all places but it will prefer the ones that has no additional value first. Then maybe I was a bit late for the check in and they first because all the others were already taken (?). This is a big supposition but I am grateful that happen, and at the same time I now realized that I should be equanimous and don’t crave this feelings but rather really live to the fullest every day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On this proposition I realized how better it is to really always try to live to the fullest. Life is short and it does not have any prefixed length. So living everyday in the present is the real life hack. And also memento more has become increasingly more important as if a person lives a life with a purpose and a direction whenever it will end it will be a good life. If someone might not have a purpose or direction that might be a bit more difficult.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let me know what you think in this regard in the comments and I will leave you with a couple of photos of my and our class in Bruxelles.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ciao!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://sebo-the-tramp.github.io/03_projects/contexts/e.jfif"
width="1600"
height="1200"
srcset="https://sebo-the-tramp.github.io/03_projects/contexts/e_hu722358435378867216.jfif 480w, https://sebo-the-tramp.github.io/03_projects/contexts/e_hu422797500594362348.jfif 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="At the EU Commission"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="133"
data-flex-basis="320px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://sebo-the-tramp.github.io/03_projects/contexts/c.jfif"
width="2000"
height="1500"
srcset="https://sebo-the-tramp.github.io/03_projects/contexts/c_hu12171015809121266458.jfif 480w, https://sebo-the-tramp.github.io/03_projects/contexts/c_hu9924231365313408728.jfif 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="At the Euregio representation in Bruxelles"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="133"
data-flex-basis="320px"
>
&lt;img src="https://sebo-the-tramp.github.io/03_projects/contexts/d.jfif"
width="1600"
height="1200"
srcset="https://sebo-the-tramp.github.io/03_projects/contexts/d_hu15004275814929729284.jfif 480w, https://sebo-the-tramp.github.io/03_projects/contexts/d_hu753058859736929890.jfif 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="At the EU Parliament"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="133"
data-flex-basis="320px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://sebo-the-tramp.github.io/03_projects/contexts/b.jfif"
width="1024"
height="768"
srcset="https://sebo-the-tramp.github.io/03_projects/contexts/b_hu15812956490927628739.jfif 480w, https://sebo-the-tramp.github.io/03_projects/contexts/b_hu14911607811920133306.jfif 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Chilling in the park"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="133"
data-flex-basis="320px"
>
&lt;img src="https://sebo-the-tramp.github.io/03_projects/contexts/a.jfif"
width="1024"
height="768"
srcset="https://sebo-the-tramp.github.io/03_projects/contexts/a_hu3636863013617844214.jfif 480w, https://sebo-the-tramp.github.io/03_projects/contexts/a_hu16046551133804725612.jfif 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Chilling at the beer factory"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="133"
data-flex-basis="320px"
>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>